

ac@sparklelabs.com: arielchuri.sparklelabs.com: 646-450-4576: Montclair, NJ

I am a designer with 20+ years of experience as an individual contributor and managing teams.

My understanding of design, from *empathy mapping* to *value opportunity analysis*, has allowed me to extract hidden value from undiscovered complications.

My understanding of technology, from letterpress to machine learning, has allowed me to produce pixel-perfect interactions that delight users.

I have created and taught projects using *augmented reality*, *design systems* creation and governance, *hardware prototyping*, *service design*, *artificial intelligence*, and *design research methodologies*.

Experience

Razorfish: Bridgestone

UX Director: 2022-2023

Managed a team of 4 UX/UI designers in a **SAFe/Agile** environment. Worked with business, product, and dev to ensure delivery of a **B2B** system for *Bridgestone/Firestone*. Developed and maintained the design process and implementation of the **Figma/Zeplin** design library.

Wunderman/Thompson: Berkley Insurance Group

UX Lead: 2021-2022

Workshopped with the client and their customers to determine stakeholder needs. Conducted **interviews**, **competitive analysis**, and **content audit** for a website redesign. Created **user-journeys** and **jobs-to-be-done** framework. Worked with the SEO and data analytics team to ensure business objectives were met.

Sotheby's

UX Lead: 2019-2021

I joined Sotheby's as part of their digital transformation initiative. I led UX designers and collaborated with multiple product owners to merge the digital and live auctions. My team brought together **client-facing**, online auctions with **point-of-sale** and administrative interfaces in a unified **design system**. Research included **observation**, **design-thinking** workshops, and interviews.

IBM

UX Lead: 2018-2019

I worked closely with IBM's digital agency to create artifacts and experiences that included **touch interfaces** for editorial publishing and **mixed reality** experiences. I held **workshops** with IBM's top clients, **rapid prototyped** with cardboard and code, and created **motion graphics** to model interactions. I designed presentations to justify our work and get stakeholder buy-in.

Unilever

UX Lead: 2017-2018

Supply-chain management moves from the sourcing of manufacturing ingredients to the store shelf. Unilever is exploring the use of **artificial intelligence** to manage this complex task. I interviewed people in the field and worked with the **AI** scientists to uncover where real value could be added into this system. Through an iterative process, I developed wireframes and UI designs for a real-world, AI supply-chain management **dashboard**.

Amazon/Comixology

UX Director: 2015-2017

Led a team of UX practitioners and creatives to implement a series of feature improvements to the subscription, purchase, and library management that positively effected **user-satisfaction**.

Successfully designed and implemented the user account and library merge program required by the company's aquisition by Amazon.

Sparkle Labs

Partner: Ongoing

- Ideation and development of educational electronics kits.
- Instructional and package design.
- Sourcing, manufacturing, and factory visits.
- Consulting and prototyping of hardware and software applications for Starcom Mediavest, Faith Popcorn, Kid Robot, Kill Screen, MoMA, Mattel, Hasbro.
- Writing articles for Make Magazine.

Parsons, The New School for Design

Professor: Ongoing

Teaching and designing courses for undergraduate and graduate students.

- **Design Research Methodology**: Introduce research and design methodologies. Apply the different techniques in a series of projects, engaging both users and experts.
- Visual & Information Design: Explore the fundamentals of visual communication and typography.
- Creative Computing / Web Design: Introduce core concepts and design patterns of programming through front end web development.
- **Physical Computing**: Create and program embedded hardware systems. Design, prototype, and test a physical interfaces.

Other Clients

Wunderman Thompson, Havas Creative, MoMA, Samsung, Calvin Klein, Morgan Stanley, Ogilvy,

Education

- MFA: Interactive Telecommunications Program, New York University, NYC
- BA: Printmaking, University of the Arts, Philadelphia

Recognition

- Guest Speaker on Design Thinking, Eurobest Conference, Lisbon, Portugal, 2011
- Gallery Hanahou solo show, New York, New York, 2010
- The 2nd Art and Science International Exhibition and Symposium, Beijing, China, 2006
- Contributor, Make Magazine, 2005 2010
- Gwang Ju Design Biennale, Gwang Ju, Korea, 2005
- American Institute of Graphic Arts, Design Ranch workshop, 2005
- New Product Showcase, Compact-Impact/TKNY, New York, NY, 2004
- Ubiquitous Computing Conference, Seattle, WA, 2003